BGM
Lucky Fest Special Talk
Thank you very much
So...
We have all the scandalous people right after the live concert.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you very much for coming.
It's hard to believe that you've just finished a live concert.
You look so fresh. Really? I was sweating like crazy.
Really? But it's getting a little cooler. Yes, it is. The wind is blowing a little bit now, and it feels good.
How about summer festivals? Are you good at them? I haven't really thought about whether I'm good at it or not.
It's hot, you know. The heat, yes. I don't like the heat.
You don't like the heat? I don't like the heat.
But I always feel like I'm going into battle.
The temperature is the same, and it's a place where new audiences come to see you,
It's a place where you have to put in a lot of energy, which is different from a one-man show.
It is true that other bands do the same.
We get a lot of new fans at festivals. There were so many people who saw us for the first time today.
Did you recognize them at all? Even when I watch them. I could tell somehow. So I asked them during the MC.
During the MC, I asked if there were many people who were seeing the show for the first time, and many of them raised their hands. It's nice to meet new people.
If I can catch them like this. How do you feel about it? I guess it's a little different from the fans.
Is it interesting? Yes, it's interesting.
Like, "Oh, you're going to get excited here?
But I don't know.
Our fans are in front of us.
They were in front of us.
It's like if we do it this way
If we did it this way, everyone in the venue would do it this way.
It's like the fans are taking the initiative.
I felt like the fans were taking the initiative.
That's right.
Fans are never in the back.
Sometimes I hear from DMs that they came to like us at festivals and started going to our one-man shows.
I hope to meet people like that today, too.
Are you good at festivals?
Maybe I'm not so good at festivals.
Maybe I'm better at one-man shows.
One-man shows are better.
I do more one-man shows throughout the year by far.
That's amazing, isn't it?
It's like we want to confirm the bond we've cultivated with the audience at festivals.
We always perform like this at festivals.
I hope we can bring it to festivals and bring new people to the festivals.
Lucky festival just finished.
What did you think of it? I'd like to ask each one of you.
Yes, I do.
Yes, but it was amazing.
I don't know, the temperature and the oden are a factor, but...
I thought it was really easy to do today, and thankfully the time of day was not too hot.
Not too hot
It wasn't too hot and it wasn't too cool, so it was really nice.
This is my first time playing at this festival, and it's become my favorite festival.
I'm sure everyone is happy about this.
Let's hear it one by one.
It was just after noon when we arrived at the festival site today under the hot sun.
The staff who showed us around in the parking lot greeted us like we were lucky.
Did you do it?
They did it and we laughed so hard.
It wasn't just the standalone?
No, no, no, no, it was really something.
We were in the parking lot in the hot sun.
I mean...
He must have been really tired, but seeing him like that, it made me feel a little bit better.
It's a festival with a sense of togetherness.
I came too, but they didn't do anything.
I didn't get to see that gag... he's so cute!
I'm so lucky...
I'm sure it's nice and warm.
I've got the impression that all summer festivals these days offer a variety of genres of music.
I thought Lucky Fest was a festival where you could hear a wider variety of music genres.
I also thought that Luckyfest was a festival where you could hear a wider variety of music genres.
I also thought it was great to see artists of different generations, some of whom have been active for a long time, on the timetable alongside the newer artists. I mean, there were people from when I was in junior high school.
There were people from when I was in junior high school, and of course there were people from today.
There were so many artists who sang songs that were popular in our generation or when we were students.
There are so many artists singing songs that were popular when I was in school, so it really stuck with me.
We had a lot of fun backstage.
It's so much fun!
We're having a lot of fun backstage.
They do it all the time.
They're always saying things like, "This song was in the drama at that time, wasn't it?
They were talking about how this song was in the drama at that time.
It's so much fun.
We're having a lot of fun.
It's great.
It's a little nostalgic, but at the same time
You're still working on it, you know.
You don't give away too much, do you?
It's like the old days.
You've been playing a lot of hit songs.
I'm glad.
So, what did you think?
I was going to say the same thing already.
It really hit a nerve with the generation.
It's great to go to a festival where you feel like you're having fun as a listener.
That's right.
Festivals that are only for your generation would be fun, but if there's a wide range of music, you can have that kind of fun.
But if you have a wide range of people, you can have that kind of fun, too.
I was happy and it was fun.
But I'm sure you've been to a lot of festivals and eaten a lot of festival food, but what about Ibaraki?
In Ibaraki, I just had that pizza with the shirasu and the pizza and the Margherita.
It was a live concert so it soaked me.
I'm sure you'll hear about it after the concert.
I saw that melon ice cream and I haven't had a chance to try it yet.
I want to eat it. There's some kind of fesmellon ice cream. Recently.
Yes, they do, don't they? Especially in Hitachinaka, isn't it?
When people come to Hitachinaka, they want to eat melon ice cream.
Yes, I do. It makes me want to eat melon ice cream.
Yes, it does. When you eat delicious food, you feel like that.
It's the best.
It's one of the best parts of festivals, isn't it?
You are currently on tour.
Oh, the tour is over.
So you just finished the national tour, including the Asian tour.
Just finished, and now the festival season has started again. It's the first one, right? That's about it. Yes, it is. It's like the beginning of the summer festival season.
But it's good. It's nice to start right after the tour. It feels like we are back. We can have that feeling.
Is that how it is? That's the way it is. Don't you feel like you're ready to go back? Live performance.
Maybe that's true. I feel that if I leave a little bit of time off, it's like a reset. So I feel that it is better for me physically and mentally to keep going as long as possible.
After the live show, I finish my tour, and then the festival starts. After the festival is over, I go back to the live show. And then the gigs start. I've been doing it for more than 10 years now.
You are an amazing band member. Don't you ever take a break? No, I don't take a break.
Not really? Not to relieve stress, but I think it's the gigs themselves.
I took a month off at the beginning of this year. You've taken a lot of time off.
That's a first. I decided to take a break to recharge my batteries.
What did you do?
I went on a trip and took it easy. Trickus.
You don't see the members anymore? No, we didn't.
We just spent time with each other.
Did you go abroad? I went abroad. We went quite a bit. Where did you go?
Kumamoto and not suddenly overseas.
Kumamoto...not overseas. I went to Korea,
I went to Korea and the Philippines. It was one month.
It was a very hard schedule. I made a mistake. I missed the schedule.
It was so hard. I didn't rest at all. It was amazing.
I have many opportunities to go abroad for work, but it was rare for me to go on a private trip, so I was able to refresh myself a lot.
Recently, Japanese bands have been invited to overseas festivals, and there have been many scandals, haven't there?
Last year, I was invited to an anime festival and a Japan festival in Brazil, and I went to Brazil for the first time.
How was it? How was Brazil?
It was far away.
It took 30 hours one way.
It was very far.
I've traveled a lot of long distances.
I've traveled a lot of long distances, so I should be well-trained.
But 30 hours took a toll on me.
Wow!
I'm a little tired.
Tired?
But there were so many people there.
I'm really glad I went.
It was like they broke down in tears the moment they saw us.
So many fans on the other side of the world?
Really!
I was so surprised!
Brazil is right behind us.
And they could remember the lyrics and sing the songs.
I thought it was amazing!
I enjoyed it.
It's great to see a Japanese band so popular overseas.
As a Japanese, I'm happy that Japanese bands are popular overseas, too.
It makes me happy.
I went to Cuba, too, and kids talked to me there.
I went to Cuba, too, and kids talked to me and said "Naruto".
I thought, "Wow, Cuba is great for anime.
He was like, "Go talk to your mom, she's Japanese.
He came up to me and said, "Naruto!
He came up to me and said, "Naruto," and I said, "Wow!
And Flo, who was on today.
That's right, she's from Brazil.
Is that right?
We were talking earlier.
I have to come back to Japan in the second half of the year.
Right?
It's going to take about six months.
I'm going on a world tour.
He said...
So you'll be on the road for 30 hours.
That's a lot of travel.
Isn't that what Scandal is doing?
Except for the Corona Disaster, we've been going overseas every once in a while since we were indies.
I've had a lot to talk about, especially with Mr. Flo.
I've been invited to some of his festivals during that time.
I felt sympathy in many areas.
I see. Is it different when you go to Japanese festivals after coming back from overseas? Not at all.
I don't know.
But the way the people in Japan get into the groove
I think it's amazing every time.
People from overseas are also free.
They all have their own way of having fun and their own way of doing things, but
But Japanese people have an amazing ability to work together and get into the same groove.
Japanese fans practice, don't they?
Do you practice?
All fans of idols practice, you know.
Do you have a store? My fans
Not at all.
But now that I think about it...
They're all here!
Maybe this is how they ride.
That's so cute!
Maybe she's learning.
It's cute.
It's so cute how they move together.
People from overseas are watching them too.
Maybe they'll get it.
In what time?
They'll imitate the culture.
Maybe in the future.
Fans like that, too.
It's interesting, when you're touring overseas.
I think you've been to Mito, but what do you think of this festival in Ibaraki Prefecture? Do you have any impression of Ibaraki?
It's been a while since I was at a live house called Maeda or Mito Light House in Ibaraki, as part of the 47 prefectures tour.
It's been a long time since I've been to Ibaraki. It was as hard as going overseas, wasn't it?
It was a lot of work.
So it had been about 6 or 7 years since then.
It was fun to be able to perform at such a close distance from the audience.
I've played in many different venues, so it's nice to be able to feel the distance from time to time.
It was nice to be able to feel the distance from time to time.
The four of you seem to be very close.
We have been together for 18 years.
It's amazing. I think it's a miracle to be in a band.
It is a miracle, isn't it?
There are not many bands that have been together for 18 years.
We are the only band in the world that has been together for 18 years.
The best in the world?
Yes, we made the Guinness World Records.
Congratulations!
We did it last year.
Guinness?
Yes, I did.
18 years?
17 years.
So you're breaking the record now?
Yes, I am.
Tell me your secret.
I could refer you to a girl band that's looking at this.
I don't care.
Like, we don't care about each other.
But I guess there are feelings that only the four of us can understand.
that only the four of us can understand.
Especially for us.
We had a very special beginning.
We started from a dance school.
That's right.
There is something special about that start that only the four of us can share.
The four of us have been standing on stage together for a long time, both negative and positive.
The feelings that only the four of us can understand each other have been with us for all these years.
I feel that the feeling that only the four of us can understand each other has connected us for all these years.
You met at a dance school, right?
That's right.
You mentioned it.
It's like, "Let's try something with those who have instruments or something.
They all just do what they want to do.
18 years. Amazing, isn't it?
It's a miracle, isn't it?
It's a Guinness Book of World Records.
You're doing great.
The goal is to continue this activity for a long time.
I think it's interesting that you don't know that.
You never know what's going to happen as you get older.
At the moment, I'm still going at the same pace.
But you never know.
That's part of it.
I'm determined to give it all I've got and give it my all.
And this festival, too.
I'm really taking care of it.
When I hear you say that...
What?
You're going to end it? Like...
Some people might be worried.
I'm always there for the clients who come to see me.
I'm always there.
I'm so grateful that they come.
I really appreciate it.
I don't know.
I don't know if they're going to stay.
I don't know if you're going to be around forever.
I've been doing this for 18 years.
It's direct, isn't it?
So...
I'm always trying to surprise them
I'm always thinking of something fun and surprising.
I'd like to continue to do it with the new four of us.
I see. I see.
Because some of our former high school fans have become mothers.
And they can't come to the show anymore.
And now that they've grown up a little bit, they're able to come again.
I feel like we've entered that phase recently.
We're in that phase, too.
They get married, stop coming, get divorced, and come back.
Life goes on, you know.
There are many people of child-rearing age, so they come here with their children after they have settled down to some extent.
But the child was....
I often hear recently that the child is now a mother, so that is something that I would not have been able to see if I had not continued the show for 18 years.
I think that is something I would not have been able to see if I had not continued for 18 years, and that is probably what makes me happiest.
I think that's probably what makes me happiest.
They come as parents and children, three generations at a time. It's amazing.
Even if I say, "You haven't changed at all," it's like there's such a long history.
You don't show any of this, do you?
I just met Sho-san from Kishida at the catering space.
Sho-san... you've collaborated with me on TV since my debut.
He's been watching us since our debut, collaborating with us on TV and performing live together.
Sho-san told me earlier that you haven't changed at all.
Is everyone eating mermaids or something? I don't know if it's true.
I don't know if it's true. I think there was a special at first.
That's right.
You used to be so happy, but you haven't changed at all. The happy is getting less and less.
I thought it was the same on the inside, and the moment I walked in, I was like...
It doesn't look like you're doing such a tough tour. It's pretty tough every year.
I'm going to make sure I never get exposed to the sun. You're exposed to the sun.
I hope you will continue to do so in the future.
Thank you very much.
Lastly, I would like to ask you...
I would appreciate it if you could give a message to our viewers.
Thank you very much.
Yes, thank you.
Thank you for your support.
And there were a lot of people that you met today.
I hope you will come and see us again at our one-man show.
We will do our best even after 18 years!
So, that's everyone from Scandal!
Thank you very much.